# Sharvari A. Sangle

**E-mail:** sharvari.sangle@gmail.com **Address:** Minneapolis, Minnesota

Phone no: 612-735-2279

Portfolio: http://sangl003.github.io/Portfolio/

Six years of experience in the GIS industry with proficiency in spatial analysis, data management, and custom development. Passionate to lead and work for the community with great people's skills and customer service experience. The unique combination of IT and GIS expertise bridges the technical gap between the two areas.

Education			
Master of Geographic Information Science	University of Minnesota	3.72	2016
Bachelor of Engineering Information Technology	University of Pune	3.76	2011
Diploma in Information technology	University of Mumbai	3.8	2007
Full stack Web developer certification	University of Minnesota		2018
VB.Net, C#, ASP.net	Seed Infotech, India		2011

## Experience

#### GIS Developer SRF Consulting Group, INC. Jan 2017 - Till date

Lead advance programming and development of cross-platform, multi-function, interactive applications, support critical GIS functions, set cartographic, data governance standards and Manage overall spatial analytics and perform competitive intelligence modeling, Administer ArcGIS Enterprise comprising of more than 100 desktop and online GIS users and managing SQL database. Perform Big Data analysis on transportation datasets to generate effective intuitive reports, dashboards and maps. Assist with business development through client presentations and proposal preparation. Act as a GIS resource on various technical committees, commission groups, initiatives etc.

#### GIS Analyst SRF Consulting Group, INC. Jan 2017 – Jan 2018

Worked cross functionally with engineers, planners and other professionals on GIS projects, determine data requirements and project specifications. Manage tasks, risks, staffing requirements, budget and client coordination. Reduced processing time for 15 Million waypoints as a part of travel pattern analysis form 40 hours to 1- minute. Created cartographically pleasing static and web maps to communicate project data to clients and stakeholders. Led database support (PostgreSQL) for Intelligent Transportation System applications.

#### GIS analyst - SEEDS Intern Minnesota Department of Transportation Sep 2016 – Dec 2016

Created Map book templates for 87 counties and over 800 cities using data driven pages, developed "Plan Your Project" byway interactive map. Updated geographic information to ensure geospatial data and maps are accurate and conducted research to compile relevant sources of geospatial information ensuring MNDOT's data accurately reflects current roadway status.

## GIS analyst Internship / GA University of Minnesota – U Services GIS June 2015 – Aug 2016

Delivered Interactive 2D and 3D web applications and wrote technical Documentation. Used JavaScript API HTML & CSS to customize web app builder templates to match branding standards. Digitized and designed Oracle databases, administered ArcGIS Server, create python tools for process automation, cartographically pleasing pdf and web maps, spatial analysis. Experience with a variety of spatial databases like road networks, asset management, land-use, imagery, lidar, survey datasets, elevations, terrains

### SDK GIS Analyst Cybertech Systems and Software Ltd, ESRI Technical Support Jan 2012 – July 2013

SDK Analyst for Tier I technologies to develop custom tools and add-ins using .Net Framework with ArcObjects, Arc Engine application, ArcGIS runtime for WPF. Submit bugs and enhancements for the software. Supported custom development for ArcGIS server JavaScript API, Flex API, Silverlight API. Help Domestic clients (US) and international clients to achieve the required functionality. Demonstrate excellent communication skills and knowledge on customer service. Train and mentor trainees.

## Skills

**GIS Platform:** ESRI suite [ArcGIS Desktop (9.3-current), Enterprise, ArcGIS Pro, ARCGIS for office, ArcGIS for auto CAD, Portal, Online, Web AppBuilder, ArcGIS for Insight, Operations dashboard, ArcGIS Collector] QGIS, Carto DB, Survey 123, ERDAS Imagine, Terra sync, Arc pad 7, Trimble GPS device, GPS Garmin device

**Developing platform:**HTML5, JavaScript, NodeJS, jQuery, NPM, Google API, Leaflet, Bootstrap, Python scripting, ARCPY, Arc Objects with C# & VB.net, VB.NET, C#, ASP.Net, SQL

Management: Agile management, Kanban, GitHub, Trello

Database: Firebase, SQL Server, SQL Express, PostgreSQL, Oracle.

Tools: Alteryx, Tableau, Visual Studio, Adobe illustrator cc, Dreamweaver, Eclipse

Interests: Painting, Dancing, Singing

# Volunteer Experience

•	Technical Presenter (GIS/LIS Consortium)	Oct 17- 2018
•	Board of Directors (Indian Association of Minnesota)	Nov 17- 2018
•	Volunteer (Minnesota Fringe Festival /Bollywood Dance Scene/ Chance for Them)	Jun-Dec 2017
•	ESRI Student assistant 2016 (ESRI)	July 2016
•	Volunteer (Courage Kenney Rehabilitation Institute)	June 2015